<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>The Spruce</title>
        <link>https://www.thespruce.com</link>
        <text>"Discover the latest in home news. We have up-to-date tips and expert advice on everything
            home-related, from decor and home renovations to gardening.
        "</text>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 19:06:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <item><componentLayouts><authorLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></authorLayout><bodyLayout><columnSpan>5</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></bodyLayout><headerImageLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><ignoreDocumentMargin>true</ignoreDocumentMargin><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin><minimumHeight>40vh</minimumHeight></headerImageLayout><introLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></introLayout><titleLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>10</bottom><top>50</top></margin></titleLayout></componentLayouts><componentTextStyles><authorStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>16</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></authorStyle><bodyStyle><fontName>Georgia</fontName><fontSize>18</fontSize><lineHeight>26</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></bodyStyle><default-subtitle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>20</fontSize><lineHeight>24</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-subtitle><default-title><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>36</fontSize><lineHeight>44</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-title><introStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Medium</fontName><fontSize>24</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></introStyle><titleStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>64</fontSize><lineHeight>74</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></titleStyle></componentTextStyles><components><element><layout>titleLayout</layout><role>title</role><text>The 7 Best Chest Freezers of 2021</text><textStyle>titleStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>introLayout</layout><role>intro</role><text>
                A great chest freezer stores food efficiently and helps you save money. We researched the best chest freezers so you can pick the one for your needs.</text><textStyle>introStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>headerImageLayout</layout><role>header</role><style><fill><URL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/zNspbDVAMMCOwvR6ZTnZBUq-lug=/2873x1881/GettyImages-170107646-88348fd278254ed5a10401bb59a935bd.jpg</URL><fillMode>cover</fillMode><type>image</type><verticalAlignment>center</verticalAlignment></fill></style></element><element><layout>authorLayout</layout><role>author</role><text>Anne Fritz</text><textStyle>authorStyle</textStyle></element><element role="body"><html>
                <p>Whether you tuck a chest freezer into a corner of your garage, kitchen, or basement, it'll be a quality solution for your frozen food storage needs. These appliances are usually modern in design, with interior lighting and temperature control settings that you can set yourself. After coming home with a particularly large haul from the store, these freezers will ensure you don't have bags of frozen kale or chicken tenders sitting out on the counter while you re-organize your top or bottom freezer.</p><p>In addition, most come with storage baskets that slide so you can easily access what you do put into them. The capacity of this appliance can range from 9 cubic feet—which is about the size of a standard freezer attached to a refrigerator—to 15 cubic feet. Before choosing a chest freezer, decide how much extra space is needed in your home and then shop accordingly.</p><p>Below, we've found the best chest freezers for a variety of budgets and needs.</p><p>Whether you like to prep your meals in advance, buy in bulk, or are a baker, you can’t go wrong with this model: the Frigidaire FFFC15M4TW. It’s so easy to spot what you’re looking for in this 14.8-cubic-foot unit, thanks to its bright interior LED lights, removable plastic baskets for organization, and a lid that stays up all on its own. This type of lid makes it possible to root around with both hands.</p><p>This freezer also has an exterior power indicator light and temperature dial which can be set from -10 to 10 degrees Fahrenheit (It’s generally recommended to set your freezer at 0 degrees.) It features a water drain for <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/how-often-should-i-defrost-my-freezer-1388710" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">easy defrosting</a>, and also comes with a safety lock and key. Whenever you need to move it around, make use of the casters and put it exactly where you need it. All in all, this large range of features makes it our pick for best overall.</p><p>The Magic Chef HMCF7W4 is another quality pick if you're searching for a chest freezer. It covers all the bases with its two bulk storage baskets, temperature dial which can be set anywhere from -8 to 6 degrees Fahrenheit, and LED lights. You likely won't have any issues finding what you're looking for, and organizing frozen pizzas and vegetables thanks to a removable divider.</p><p>Now, this model is not frost-free or self-defrosting. You'll have to use the included drain to defrost the unit yourself. In addition, this piece isn't quite as spacious as others on the market, but makes the most of its 7.0 cubic feet of interior space. If you take it to a college dorm or vacation home, you'll enjoy the recessed handle, and how sleek and simple this appliance looks wherever it goes.</p><p>If you're hoping to spend less on a chest freezer, the Hotpoint HCM9DMWW is for you. It has an exterior dial for temperature control with seven different settings, so you can be certain your food is being kept at the ideal temperature. Notable features also include a high-temp warning light that automatically turns on when the freezer is open, and a green power light that makes it clear when it’s on and running correctly.</p><p>In addition, an interior LED light turns on when the lid is lifted, and there are two sliding, bulk <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/how-to-organize-a-freezer-5085778" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">storage baskets</a> that make it easy for you to store and locate all your favorite foods quickly. With a built-in defrost drain, and a lock and key, this model certainly treats you to the works without requiring you to spend a lot.</p><p>This commercial-grade <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/freezer-chest-versus-upright-freezer-1908647" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">chest freezer</a> from SABA would work well in a cabin, pool house, or anywhere you want to serve up cold beverages or ice cream to friends and groups. It has forced air cooling to cool the bottles on top—aka the ones you just put in—first. The stainless steel glide lids are easy to open and close as well, even for kids.</p><p>This model has a digital temperature control and auto defrost which alone makes it worth the extra cost. It comes with a key so you can lock it whenever you’re not around, and wheels so you can move it easily. Plus, the black and stainless steel finish is stylish and less of an eyesore in any room.</p><p>You'll never run out of space to store your favorite meals and snacks with the GE FCM22DLWW. This model has a whopping 21.7 cubic feet of storage space, that is thoughtfully designed with five bulk storage baskets and four dividers. You can customize the dividers so that the appliance fits your specific lifestyle and needs, and then lock the entire piece when you're done organizing to keep food safe. If you're taking this freezer on-the-go—say, for a camping or hunting trip—the lock can be very helpful and put your mind at ease.</p><p>In addition to those notable design features, this GE chest freezer also includes a temperature alarm and power indicator. The piece is Energy Star-certified so you don't have to stress about it racking up your energy bill, either. Just be aware: the temperature alarm can be a little touchy at times, and go off even when the piece is at the right temperature.</p><p>Whether you're on vacation or setting up an extra freezer in your RV, you want a piece that's reliable, portable, and flexible. Enter, the Whynter FM-452SG: a pick that doesn't necessarily look stylish, but will certainly get the job done. It has 1.48 cubic feet of interior space, which is outfitted with two storage baskets for all your organization needs. The internal temperature of the piece can be adjusted to any temperature between -8 and 50 degrees Fahrenheit.</p><p>Now, at 52 pounds, this piece is certainly a bit heavy to carry. You'll want to set it up at the beginning of your trip in a place that's easy to reach, so you can grab a snack, and also manually defrost the appliance as needed. The appliance makes up for this weight by being compatible with even a 12-Volt DC outlet. This type of outlet is common on boats and RVs, where power sources are a bit limited.</p><p>Not every chest freezer can perform in all temperatures, from very cold to very hot, so if you want to keep one in your garage, it’s worth it to splurge on a unit that can handle the extremes. The GE FCM11PHWW is a great pick, as it can work in temperatures ranging from 0 to 110 degrees Fahrenheit. Ultimately, it's able to be <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/freezer-installation-steps-1907757" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">installed in an area</a> that's not climate controlled.</p><p>Though it’s medium-sized, it’s <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/what-is-energy-star-1908482" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">Energy Star-rated</a>, meaning it runs efficiently and without taking up many resources. It won’t rack up new charges on your electric bill. Other benefits include three sliding storage baskets, an interior light to help you find what you’re looking for, and an exterior power light so you can feel very assured that it’s working.</p><h2>What to Look for in a Chest Freezer</h2><h3>Capacity</h3><p>The amount of space in a chest freezer, which determines how much you can store, can range from 3 to 22 cubic feet. An average chest freezer typically has about 15 cubic feet of interior space, which is about 112 liquid gallons. When you're shopping for a new model, you'll want to keep in mind that more capacity means the model will be wider and take up a larger spot in your garage or home. Finding the balance between storage and living space may be essential.</p><h3>Organization options</h3><p>Unlike upright freezers, chest freezers don't usually have shelving that helps keep your frozen goods organized. Instead, chest freezers have dividers and baskets, which you can use to separate dinners from meats, fruit, or baked goods. The average chest freezer has two or three storage baskets, while more spacious and high-end models may have up to five. Some of these baskets can be sliding, and others will be removable, which is ideal for a manually-defrosting model.</p><h3>Manual vs. automatic defrosting</h3><p>If your chest freezer manually defrosts, then you will need to maintain it when ice and frost builds up in the interior. Once the build up becomes a quarter-inch thick, you'll need to unplug your model, take everything out of it, and chip away at the ice and frost. After the ice and frost has been removed and is melted away, you can drain the unit and plug it back in. If your chest freezer automatically defrosts, or is considered frost-free or self-defrosting, internal coils will occasionally heat up and keep frost at bay. This option is more expensive to operate, and purchase upfront, but is easier to use.</p><h2>Standout Features</h2><h3>Safety lock</h3><p>If your chest freezer has a safety lock, you're able to secure what you're storing inside. This feature is particularly handy if you plan on leaving your freezer in a garage, or frequently entertain. You can lock the appliance and feel comfortable knowing that there will be no unwanted entry. Typically, the safety lock is paired with a physical key or key fob, which you should store in a safe, accessible spot.</p><h3>Garage-ready design</h3><p>Any household that wants extra storage, but doesn't want to set up a bulky appliance in their kitchen should look for a chest freezer with a garage-ready design. This type of design ensures the appliance will run properly, whether the external temperature is very hot or very cold. In other words, your goods won't go bad, and will remain in a stable internal environment. Not all freezers are garage-ready, so it's important to look for this feature.</p><h3>Exterior power light</h3><p>It can be hard to tell if your chest freezer is on and running. Even if it's plugged in, without any sort of indicator, you may worry the appliance isn't properly storing your food. An exterior power light creates a small glow on the ground near the appliance, so you know it's working properly. It's very suitable for households that aren't quick to trust their appliances, and are planning to keep their chest freezer on at all times.</p><h2>FAQs</h2><h3>How long does a chest freezer last?</h3><p>On average, a chest freezer lasts 14 years. This is longer than a standard refrigerator, which typically lasts around 10 years. You can extend your freezer's lifespan by properly maintaining it and storing it in the proper conditions. For example, if your freezer is not a garage-ready model, keep it in a kitchen or temperature-controlled basement. Make sure there's no ice build up, and manually defrost it when needed. In addition, make sure the lid is closed tight after opening it, so the unit doesn't have to work harder than usual.</p><h3>How do I organize a chest freezer?</h3><p>When it comes to organizing a chest freezer, you'll want to really make use of the included baskets or dividers. Group similar items together, and give them their own designated basket. Stack baskets and bins for easy access to the items you need. In addition, label your meats, fruits, and vegetables with a "best by" date, and put the oldest items on top, so you know to use them first. For more, check out our guide on <a href="https://www.thespruceeats.com/how-to-organize-the-freezer-4802672" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="externalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="nofollow">how to organize a freezer</a>.</p><h3>How much energy does a chest freezer use?</h3><p>Chest freezers typically <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/freezer-chest-versus-upright-freezer-1908647" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">use less energy</a> than their upright counterparts. This is because of the quality of their insulation, which lines the walls and even helps keep your food cold during power outages. On average, a chest freezer will use 250 kWh per year, while upright freezers can use almost 500 kWH per year. If you don't fill your freezer to the brim and care for it properly, this number may go down a bit.</p><h2>Why Trust The Spruce?</h2><p>This article was edited and updated by <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/marisa-casciano-5091570" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marisa Casciano</a>, who is the large appliance expert for The Spruce. Throughout her career, she's researched the ins and outs of air purifiers, dishwashers, cooktops, and more in the home and lifestyle space. As an avid cook, she understands the need for extra storage space, and a model that can withstand different temperatures, locations, and uses.</p></html></element></components><documentStyle><backgroundColor>#f6f6f6</backgroundColor></documentStyle><identifier>https://www.thespruce.com/best-chest-freezers-4150012</identifier><language>en</language><layout><columns>7</columns><gutter>40</gutter><margin>70</margin><width>1024</width></layout><metadata><excerpt>
                A great chest freezer stores food efficiently and helps you save money. We researched the best chest freezers so you can pick the one for your needs.</excerpt><thumbnailURL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/zNspbDVAMMCOwvR6ZTnZBUq-lug=/2873x1881/GettyImages-170107646-88348fd278254ed5a10401bb59a935bd.jpg</thumbnailURL></metadata><subtitle>Get more at <a href="http://www.thespruce.com">The Spruce</a>.</subtitle><title>
                A great chest freezer stores food efficiently and helps you save money. We researched the best chest freezers so you can pick the one for your needs.</title><version>1.0</version></item>
        <item><componentLayouts><authorLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></authorLayout><bodyLayout><columnSpan>5</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></bodyLayout><headerImageLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><ignoreDocumentMargin>true</ignoreDocumentMargin><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin><minimumHeight>40vh</minimumHeight></headerImageLayout><introLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></introLayout><titleLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>10</bottom><top>50</top></margin></titleLayout></componentLayouts><componentTextStyles><authorStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>16</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></authorStyle><bodyStyle><fontName>Georgia</fontName><fontSize>18</fontSize><lineHeight>26</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></bodyStyle><default-subtitle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>20</fontSize><lineHeight>24</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-subtitle><default-title><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>36</fontSize><lineHeight>44</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-title><introStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Medium</fontName><fontSize>24</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></introStyle><titleStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>64</fontSize><lineHeight>74</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></titleStyle></componentTextStyles><components><element><layout>titleLayout</layout><role>title</role><text>The 8 Best Vacuums at Walmart</text><textStyle>titleStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>introLayout</layout><role>intro</role><text>
                Walmart has a vast selection of vacuums that are powerful and tough on dirt that sport some key features. We researched the options that might be right for you.</text><textStyle>introStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>headerImageLayout</layout><role>header</role><style><fill><URL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/oKKYkRtHN9Z8aUmftofA-ONIPAs=/2121x1414/GettyImages-544723346-5c659014c9e77c000166294c.jpg</URL><fillMode>cover</fillMode><type>image</type><verticalAlignment>center</verticalAlignment></fill></style></element><element><layout>authorLayout</layout><role>author</role><text>Ashley Knierim</text><textStyle>authorStyle</textStyle></element><element role="body"><html>
                <p>When it comes to ultra convenient, one-stop shopping, few retailers can compare to Walmart. Specifically, the megastore is a great source for home goods, from on-trend decor to lovely bathroom fixtures to vacuums. For our purposes here, we'll focus on the great options to be found in the latter category.</p><p>Walmart stocks a wide variety of manufacturers, including <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/new-vacuum-cleaner-cost-1901196" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">affordable</a> household names like Hoover, luxe brands like Dyson, and cutting-edge companies like Eufy. Whether you prefer a canister model or are concerned about removing allergens from your home, Walmart carries a vacuum that will meet <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/vacuum-cleaner-buying-guide-1909001" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="2" rel="noopener noreferrer">your needs</a>.</p><p>Here, our picks for the best vacuum cleaners available at Walmart now.</p><p>It’s great for surfaces of all types, working to remove even deeply embedded dirt and hair. A high-capacity tank means you’ll spend less time emptying out its contents—and since the filter can be washed, you won’t have to replace it often. At a little over 13 pounds, it’s lightweight enough to clean all around your home​ and includes a brush, extender and crevice tool to clean in those hard-to-reach corners.</p><p>The BISSELL PowerForce Helix vacuum has surprisingly powerful suction for being on the smaller side. Plus, the canister is well-designed, making it easy to empty out dirt into the trash without accidental spills (a common issue with some bagless vacuums).</p><p>Canister vacuums are designed differently than their upright cousins, with a cleaning nozzle linked to the vacuum by a hose. Eureka’s Mighty Mite canister vacuum is compact and lightweight at 8.5 pounds but includes a powerful motor that effectively cleans any surface. The benefit of the canister design is that it’s highly versatile, making it easier to clean above the floor than it would be using an upright vacuum. Eureka includes two extension wands, a crevice tool and an upholstery brush with the main vacuum, so it’s a breeze to take its cleaning power wherever you need it.</p><p>You can’t beat this vacuum for the value, and it can clean everything from the furniture to the walls. It’s particularly good on staircases​ since you can carry it from step to step with little effort.</p><p>For lighter, hands-free cleaning, the Eufy RoboVac 15T is a solid pick. Like other robotic vacuums, this model roams around your home cleaning up hair, dirt, and dust without your help. At less than 3 inches tall, it can get dust bunnies under dressers and couches, and can run for up to 100 minutes at a time before it needs to dock and recharge.</p><p>While this option doesn't have some of the newer features of other vacuums, like floor mapping or smart home compatibility, it's a good choice to keep your floors tidy in between deeper cleans.</p><p>If you suffer from allergies, pet hair is basically your kryptonite. And as hard is it can be to stay on top of the buildup, a vacuum designed with your needs in mind is a great way to fight back against fur. Hoover’s Total Home Pet vacuum includes numerous features that help sweep away pet hair, like a brush roll that you can activate for carpets and turn off for hardwoods. It also comes with various multipurpose pet hair tools to help lift even the most stubborn fur, as well as an odor-absorbing filter to keep pet-related smells to a minimum.</p><p>Who says you need a huge, closet-filling vacuum to take care of the toughest dirt? Black & Decker’s Dustbuster packs a ton of high-powered suction into a tiny package just over 2.5 pounds. It’s great for cleaning high-up shelves, inside cabinets, in your car—and, well, pretty much anywhere else. The bowl and filter are fully washable and easy to empty, while a simple brush attachment makes it easy to transition to cleaning upholstery.</p><p>The Dustbuster holds its charge for a long time (it takes about four hours to reach full power), and handles easily thanks to its light weight. The flip-up brush is also surprisingly multifaceted—it should come in handy for cleaning baseboards.</p><p>A cordless stick vacuum like Dyson’s V8 saves on space but doesn't skim on power. For as long as 40 minutes at a time, this model removes dirt from hard floors and rugs alike. The mini motorized tool is particularly useful when it comes to dredging up tracked-in debris and pet hair.</p><p>The V8 is a breeze to use, saving you time on quick messes while providing an intensive clean, thanks in no small part to its whole-machine HEPA filtration system, which efficiently traps allergens and expels fresh air. Then, when the time comes to empty the dust cup, you can do so with the push of a single, hassle-free button.</p><p>When cleaning an area rug or carpeted room, you don't just want your vacuum to remove surface-level dirt but embedded debris, as well. You can trust the Hoover Elite Rewind vacuum to tackle both tasks, thanks to its powerful, adjustable suction technology that's designed to lift away messes, even from high pile carpets. In its wake, this model leaves carpets and floors deeply clean: Its HEPA media filter and AllergenBlock System traps 97 percent of dust, dander, and other irritating particles. And, its large dust cup ensures less frequent emptying and longer cleaning times.</p><p>The 25-foot power cord helps users clean whole rooms from one outlet and, when cleanup is over, it seamlessly retracts back into the vacuum's stand. An assortment of tools comes with the vacuum itself, including a pet turbo tool, dust brush, and crevice tool. The cleaning hose extends up to 12 feet to clean high-up areas or under furniture. Whether you're dealing with a fully carpeted second floor or a heavily trafficked area rug, you can rest assured that this Hoover will thoroughly clean it.</p><p>While a normal vacuum can usually tackle both carpet and hardwood, you might want to look into a product that specializes in one or the other, especially if most of your home is one floor type. Bissell’s Hard Floor Expert Canister Vacuum offers a powerful clean without damaging your floor, with felt treads on the wheels that won’t leave a mark and a switch that lets you control the level of suction. The bristles of the brush are also softer than what you’ll find on other models. And as with other canister-style vacuums, it’s lightweight, maneuverable and cleans up easily—the tank opens from the bottom, reducing the potential for mess.</p><p>The Bissell’s Hard Floor Expert vacuum is easy to carry around and does a great job of cleaning hardwood floors without marking them up. The telescoping wand also makes it easy to clean upholstery, shelves, and other above-floor areas.</p><h2>What to Look for in a Vacuum at Walmart</h2><h3>Type</h3><p>Keeping your cleaning priorities in mind while you browse Walmart's wide selection will help you determine what type of vacuum is right for you. Whole-home cleaning across multiple floor surfaces can be accomplished with an upright vacuum, while messes in smaller spaces or above-floor areas are better tackled by a stick or handheld vacuum. Hands-off cleaning is also an option, as affordable robotic vacuums are also available at Walmart.</p><h3>Weight</h3><p>If you're looking for a portable vacuum that won't be a pain to lug up and down stairs, take note of how much it weighs before making your purchase. Stick and canister vacuums tend to be lighter than upright vacuums, but they might not offer the same array of attachments that you'll find with a heavier upright model.</p><h3>Attachments</h3><p>While they'll add weight to your vacuum, attachments will help you clean more of your home with one machine. An upholstery brush will keep your furniture crumb-free, a crevice tool will reach into nooks and crannies all over the house, and an extension hose will clear away overhead cobwebs and dust. If your chief concern is simply cleaning your floors, you might not need many attachments, but they will undoubtedly make your vacuum more versatile.</p><h2>FAQs</h2><h3>When is the best time to buy a vacuum from Walmart?</h3><p>While Black Friday, Cyber Monday, and the winter holiday season are all excellent times to get a great deal on a vacuum at Walmart, the absolute <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/best-time-of-year-to-buy-a-vacuum-1387763#the-best-times-to-buy-a-vacuum" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">best time of year to shop for a vacuum</a> is actually the spring. From March to May, more people are cleaning their homes than they are in the winter, which inspires many retailers to run sales on vacuums, and Walmart is no exception. There's also the fact that new models often come out in June, so retailers need to make space by selling out their older models. Keep an eye out for added sales right before the turn of the month.</p><h3>What vacuum brands does Walmart carry?</h3><p>You can expect to find most big name brands at Walmart, including Dyson, Bissell, Hoover, Shark, Eureka, Roomba, and Dirt Devil. If you shop online, Walmart's site even offers guides and shopping modules to help you find the brand that best suits your cleaning needs.</p><h3>How often should I replace a vacuum cleaner?</h3><p>Most vacuums will last for <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/lifespan-of-small-appliances-4169933" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">about eight years</a>. If you maintain it regularly and don't use it on heavy or <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/dont-mistreat-vacuum-cleaner-1901204" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="2">improper messes</a>, you may be able to use your vacuum for even longer. Sturdy models like upright vacuums may last longer than, say, robotic vacuums.</p><h3>Should I use a bagged or bagless vacuum?</h3><p>Both types of vacuums have plenty to offer the user, from suction power to dust capacity. Which type you choose mostly comes down to personal preferences and needs. If you don't mind spending money on replacement bags and want to make sure the dust your vacuum picks up gets tightly sealed away, a bagged vacuum will work well for you. On the other hand, you may be happier with a bagless vacuum if you don't want the added expense of replacement bags.</p><h2>Why Trust The Spruce?</h2><p>This article was written by <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/sara-coughlin-5091571" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">Sara Coughlin</a>, a freelance writer and The Spruce’s small appliances expert. From canister models to dustbusters, she’s researched what it takes for a vacuum to stand out in a vast and broad market—and what to look for in up-and-coming models.</p></html></element></components><documentStyle><backgroundColor>#f6f6f6</backgroundColor></documentStyle><identifier>https://www.thespruce.com/best-vacuums-at-walmart-4173210</identifier><language>en</language><layout><columns>7</columns><gutter>40</gutter><margin>70</margin><width>1024</width></layout><metadata><excerpt>
                Walmart has a vast selection of vacuums that are powerful and tough on dirt that sport some key features. We researched the options that might be right for you.</excerpt><thumbnailURL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/oKKYkRtHN9Z8aUmftofA-ONIPAs=/2121x1414/GettyImages-544723346-5c659014c9e77c000166294c.jpg</thumbnailURL></metadata><subtitle>Get more at <a href="http://www.thespruce.com">The Spruce</a>.</subtitle><title>
                Walmart has a vast selection of vacuums that are powerful and tough on dirt that sport some key features. We researched the options that might be right for you.</title><version>1.0</version></item>
        <item><componentLayouts><authorLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></authorLayout><bodyLayout><columnSpan>5</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></bodyLayout><headerImageLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><ignoreDocumentMargin>true</ignoreDocumentMargin><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin><minimumHeight>40vh</minimumHeight></headerImageLayout><introLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></introLayout><titleLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>10</bottom><top>50</top></margin></titleLayout></componentLayouts><componentTextStyles><authorStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>16</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></authorStyle><bodyStyle><fontName>Georgia</fontName><fontSize>18</fontSize><lineHeight>26</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></bodyStyle><default-subtitle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>20</fontSize><lineHeight>24</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-subtitle><default-title><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>36</fontSize><lineHeight>44</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-title><introStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Medium</fontName><fontSize>24</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></introStyle><titleStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>64</fontSize><lineHeight>74</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></titleStyle></componentTextStyles><components><element><layout>titleLayout</layout><role>title</role><text>Samara Fruit Tree Profile</text><textStyle>titleStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>introLayout</layout><role>intro</role><text>
                Samara seeds are surrounded by a papery wing that, when the wind blows, carries the seeds farther away than most other fruit seeds.</text><textStyle>introStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>headerImageLayout</layout><role>header</role><style><fill><URL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/a8Tj7cE0paFoAmBzsfcHe3vLNCs=/5322x3542/samara-fruit-3269469-01-8b9cc8b6c2914b19b374058d71a579ab.jpg</URL><fillMode>cover</fillMode><type>image</type><verticalAlignment>center</verticalAlignment></fill></style></element><element><layout>authorLayout</layout><role>author</role><text>Vanessa Richins Myers</text><textStyle>authorStyle</textStyle></element><element role="body"><html>
                <figure><img src="https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/a8Tj7cE0paFoAmBzsfcHe3vLNCs=/5322x3542/samara-fruit-3269469-01-8b9cc8b6c2914b19b374058d71a579ab.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Samara fruit with orange wings closeup" width="5322" height="3542" /><figcaption><span class="copyright">The Spruce / K. Dave</span></figcaption></figure><p>A samara is often found in large groups on a tree and not all samaras look alike. One familiar type of samara is the double-winged one found on <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/thirteen-species-of-maple-trees-3269671" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">maple trees</a> (<em>Acer spp.</em>). <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/twelve-species-of-ash-trees-3269661" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="2">Ash trees</a> (<em>Fraxinus spp.</em>) produce a samara that features a single elongated wing. <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/ten-species-of-elm-trees-3269656" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="3">Elm trees</a> (<em>Ulmus spp.</em>) produce samaras where the seed is located in the middle of a papery circle. These flowering plants all produce samara fruits after blooming.</p><figure><img src="https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/Br-FbrGnl7lUbGvhNz5TG3Z7TUM=/4169x2775/samara-fruit-3269469-03-db16f1920c6b4570a29f473ad9353640.jpg" alt="Samara fruit with orange wings closeup" width="4169" height="2775" /><figcaption><span class="copyright">The Spruce / K. Dave</span></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/dl6qIS7HK-b2UuKfYQ4rQL0WIq0=/4268x2849/samara-fruit-3269469-04-3eee2088eaf9477780dcbc27a6b4f7b0.jpg" alt="Samara fruit with orange wings and leaves in branches" width="4268" height="2849" /><figcaption><span class="copyright">The Spruce / K. Dave</span></figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/y-wXIUFdtLDlt5HG0wcHzl_jYrI=/3282x4921/samara-fruit-3269469-02-421f7a0ec1ef4eaca7cc2de91c926bec.jpg" alt="Samara fruit with orange wings and buds on branches" width="3282" height="4921" /><figcaption><span class="copyright">The Spruce / K. Dave</span></figcaption></figure><p>Examples of other trees and shrubs that produce samaras:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.thespruce.com/common-hoptree-plant-profile-4772361" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">Common hoptree</a> (<em>Ptelea trifoliata</em>)</li><li><em>Flabellaria paniculata</em> (a woody African vine)</li><li><a href="https://www.thespruce.com/twenty-invasive-trees-3269655" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="2">Tree of heaven</a> (<em>Ailanthus altissima</em>)</li><li><a href="https://www.thespruce.com/tulip-tree-growing-tips-3269351" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="3">Tulip tree</a> (<em>Liriodendron tulipifera</em>)</li><li>Also, one of the few legumes that produce a samara is the Tipu tree of South America.</li></ul><h2>Samara Fruit Tree Examples, Characteristics, and Care</h2><p>One example of a tree that produces samara fruit is the <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/growing-the-red-maple-acer-rubrum-3269321" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">Red Maple</a><em> (Acer rubrum). </em>It is a deciduous tree, native to Eastern North America from Quebec to Minnesota south to Florida and eastern Texas. In northern states, the Red Maple usually grows in wet bottomland, river flood plains, and wet woods. In the midwest, it tends to grow in drier, rocky upland areas. It is very cold hardy in USDA Zones 3 through 9. Spreading 30 to 50 feet wide, it grows 40 to 70 feet tall with a rounded to oval crown. Red maples grow faster than Norway or sugar maples, but slower than silver maples. All emerging new growth in the form of leaves, leafstalks, twigs, flowers, fruit, and fall foliage are red or tinged with red. Flowers are typically red, sometimes yellow, in large clusters, blooming from March to April. After the flowers, come the leaves. The leaves start dark green above and gray green below. They are 2 to 5 inches long with 3 or 5 primary triangular-shaped, toothed, pointed lobes. Samara fruit is also initially reddish producing a two-winged samara.</p><p>Winged Elm (<em><a href="https://www.thespruce.com/ten-species-of-elm-trees-3269656" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">Ulmus</a> alata</em>) is another deciduous tree that gives way to samaras. This elm is native to southern Virginia west to Kentucky, southern Indiana and Illinois, and central Missouri; south to central Oklahoma and southeastern Texas; and east to central Florida. It also grows in Maryland. When placed in an open area, branches arch upward to create a rounded crown. In a forested site, the tree grows taller and straighter. Naturally, Winged Elm can be seen growing freely in rock outcrops, dry wooded areas, and fields. Bark is red-brown to ash gray. Leaves have doubly toothed margins. In fall, they turn yellow and in late winter, small red flowers mature in clusters. The tree produces 1/4- to 1/2-inch flattened samara with hairy margins. Other common names for the Winged Elm are Cork Elm, Small Leaf Elm, Wahoo Winged Elm, and Witch Elm. Prune this tree regularly to prevent it from growing multiple trunks.</p><p>Common hoptree (<em>Ptelea trifoliata</em>) is native to Eastern and central United States, hardy in Zones 4 through 9. This native, deciduous tree is sometimes considered a shrub because it grows a modest 15 to 20 feet tall and wide. The hoptree is dense and rounded, making it an ideal specimen for a flowering hedge. Naturally, it grows in open woods, glades, ravines, thickets, and prairies. Leaves are shiny, dark green, each two to five inches long, turning greenish yellow in autumn. Fragrant, tiny clusters of tiny greenish white flowers bloom in late spring. These clusters of flowers produce clusters of seeds, each seed encased in a thin, winged one-inch samara. Seeds mature in late summer and last through most of winter. The common name of hoptree refers to the prior use of seeds as a substitute for hops. Other common names include wafer ash and stinking ash.</p><h3>Light</h3><p>Grow Red Maple and Winged Elm in full sun to part shade. Hoptrees can tolerate full sun but thrive in part shade to full shade.</p><h3>Soil</h3><p>While Red Maple will tolerate a wide range of soils, it prefers moist, slightly acidic soil that is well-draining. Winged Elm prefers moist to dry conditions in a variety of soil types that contain loam, clay, sand, or rock. Hoptree will also grow in dry to medium well-drained conditions.</p><h3>Water</h3><p>Plant Red Maples in a rain garden or another site where it is easy to maintain a medium to wet environment. Give Winged Elms and Hoptrees dry to medium moisture.</p><h2>Are Samara Fruit Trees Toxic?</h2><p>Be sure to research each tree, shrub, or plant for their toxicity. Red Maple is toxic to horses, but non-toxic to dogs and cats, according to the ASPCA. Wilted leaves are the most toxic part of the plant. Symptoms of poisoning include "destruction of red blood cells (anemia), weakness, dark urine, difficulty breathing, abortion, [and] death."</p><p>Tree of Heaven leaves are toxic to domestic animals, according to Purdue University, which also cautions that gardeners may experience rashes from the leaves and hay fever from the plant's pollen. However, the hoptree and tulip tree are largely known as non-toxic.</p><h2>Harvesting Maple Seeds </h2><p>Maple seeds are more than a toy; they also have a pod with edible seeds inside. Remove the outer covering before eating the seeds from maple trees. When seeds are young and green in spring, they are known to be the most pleasant tasting. Sprinkle them into a salad or stir-fry or mix them into mashed potatoes. Since different varieties of maples produce samaras at different times of the year in certain areas, seeds might be available for harvest and consumption for an extended period. Store the seeds to continue eating them through summer, fall, and perhaps winter if you have enough to last a full year. Roast or boil them if mature seeds taste bitter.</p><h2>Common Pests and Diseases</h2><p>Aphids, borers, scale, and caterpillars are common pests to the Red Maple. Leafhoppers can cause the most substantial damage. Keep an eye out for verticillium wilt, canker, fungal leaf spot, and root rots. Branches are prone to breakage by wind and ice.</p><p>Borers, scale, and caterpillars may also attack the Winged Elm. Watch for beetles and leaf miners too. This tree is especially vulnerable to <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/dutch-elm-disease-on-american-elm-trees-2131195" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">Dutch Elm Disease</a>. Powdery mildew, phloem necrosis, cankers, and leaf spots can also cause issues on stressed trees.</p></html></element></components><documentStyle><backgroundColor>#f6f6f6</backgroundColor></documentStyle><identifier>https://www.thespruce.com/samara-fruit-3269469</identifier><language>en</language><layout><columns>7</columns><gutter>40</gutter><margin>70</margin><width>1024</width></layout><metadata><excerpt>
                Samara seeds are surrounded by a papery wing that, when the wind blows, carries the seeds farther away than most other fruit seeds.</excerpt><thumbnailURL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/a8Tj7cE0paFoAmBzsfcHe3vLNCs=/5322x3542/samara-fruit-3269469-01-8b9cc8b6c2914b19b374058d71a579ab.jpg</thumbnailURL></metadata><subtitle>Get more at <a href="http://www.thespruce.com">The Spruce</a>.</subtitle><title>
                Samara seeds are surrounded by a papery wing that, when the wind blows, carries the seeds farther away than most other fruit seeds.</title><version>1.0</version></item>
        <item><componentLayouts><authorLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></authorLayout><bodyLayout><columnSpan>5</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></bodyLayout><headerImageLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><ignoreDocumentMargin>true</ignoreDocumentMargin><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin><minimumHeight>40vh</minimumHeight></headerImageLayout><introLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>15</bottom><top>15</top></margin></introLayout><titleLayout><columnSpan>7</columnSpan><columnStart>0</columnStart><margin><bottom>10</bottom><top>50</top></margin></titleLayout></componentLayouts><componentTextStyles><authorStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>16</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></authorStyle><bodyStyle><fontName>Georgia</fontName><fontSize>18</fontSize><lineHeight>26</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></bodyStyle><default-subtitle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>20</fontSize><lineHeight>24</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-subtitle><default-title><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Thin</fontName><fontSize>36</fontSize><lineHeight>44</lineHeight><textAlignment>center</textAlignment><textColor>#2F2F2F</textColor></default-title><introStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Medium</fontName><fontSize>24</fontSize><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></introStyle><titleStyle><fontName>HelveticaNeue-Bold</fontName><fontSize>64</fontSize><lineHeight>74</lineHeight><textAlignment>left</textAlignment><textColor>#000</textColor></titleStyle></componentTextStyles><components><element><layout>titleLayout</layout><role>title</role><text>The 7 Best Drill Presses of 2021</text><textStyle>titleStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>introLayout</layout><role>intro</role><text>
                A good drill press is powerful, easy to control, and durable. We researched the features of the best models so you can pick the right ones for your projects.</text><textStyle>introStyle</textStyle></element><element><layout>headerImageLayout</layout><role>header</role><style><fill><URL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/trJ5F48aBRwG7M-AlNnLRGfLgCY=/759x1500/715RIGooSGL._SL1500_-59ea5516845b340011e4144c.jpg</URL><fillMode>cover</fillMode><type>image</type><verticalAlignment>center</verticalAlignment></fill></style></element><element><layout>authorLayout</layout><role>author</role><text>Michelle Ullman</text><textStyle>authorStyle</textStyle></element><element role="body"><html>
                <p>Drill presses are stationary tools–some stand on the floor while others sit on a workbench–with a sturdy and adjustable platform to hold the object being drilled, and an overhead chuck that holds the drill bit in place. Like a portable handheld drill, a drill press is a tool for making holes in wood or other hard materials, but drill presses go far beyond handheld drills in terms of power and precision.</p><p>A handheld drill is sufficient if you merely need to occasionally drill holes into wood for simple repairs or construction. But for drilling into very hard wood or metal, drilling through thick pieces of wood, producing large holes, drilling <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/how-to-drill-at-an-angle-1822332" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">at an angle</a>, or achieving the utmost in accuracy, a drill press is the tool of choice. We researched the top drill presses available today, and then whittled down the choices to those we feel are best in their categories.</p><p>Here are the best drill presses on the market.</p><p>It is all too easy to find the wrong drill press for your needs while shopping. Plenty of options promise the power you need for most construction projects but fail to deliver when needed. The WEN 12-Inch Variable Press, with a 12-inch swing and 3-1/8-inch stroke distance, is designed to skip the overselling and simply offers a powerful, <a href="https://www.thesprucecrafts.com/how-to-align-your-drill-press-3537091" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="externalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">straightforward drill press</a> for your shop. With a maximum speed of 3,200 rpm and variable speed dial, the power and control this top choice press offers ​is clear.</p><p>The benefit of a variable speed dial is you can change the speed while maintaining the same power and torque you may need for denser materials. Using high-quality bearings and a rigid frame, the body of this drill press will resist heavy abuse while extending the life of the inner workings of the power tool. If you need a drill press you can count on to work time and time again, this option is hard to beat.</p><p>If you just want a drill press for precision work on small items such as jewelry, shells, wood trim, or model making, there’s no need for a large tool that will take up lots of space and provide more muscle than you need. Instead, consider the Eurotool DRL-300.00 Small Benchtop Drill Press.</p><p>With a platform measuring a mere 6.75 inches x 6.75 inches, and an overall size of 10 x 12 x 8 inches, the drill press easily fits into any <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/workshop-storage-ideas-5079571" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">workspace</a>. But while it may be small, it’s not without power, although it’s certainly not designed for tackling the toughest drilling jobs.</p><p>The 110-volt motor achieves a top speed of 8,500 rpm, and there are three speed settings to choose from. The <strong>¼</strong>-inch Jacobs chuck accepts bits up to 6.5 mm.</p><p>Not a true drill press, but rather, a workstation that allows you to use your Dremel rotary tool in a similar manner to a drill press, this workstation/drill press fits into the category of “small but mighty,” and is perfect for delicate tasks such as crafts, jewelry, or work on electronics. Your rotary tool fits into the workstation, allowing you to angle the tool at a variety of angles for your needs.</p><p>The workstation screws into a worktable for stability without taking up too much valuable space. Note, however, that it does not include the Dremel rotary tool; you'll need to purchase that separately if you don't already own one.</p><p>For the price, you actually get one of the most flexible drill presses available. The flex shaft attachment works with the drill to allow you to rotate the head for angled holes up to 90 degrees horizontal. A tool holder and router mount extend the capabilities of this press, enabling other work such as plunge routing and sanding/grinding to be done all in one workstation.</p><p>If you don’t mind giving up some performance and control out of a drill press, the WEN 4208 is a reasonably priced alternative that won’t break the bank. The press sacrifices the more flexible variable control dial for a five speed switch that extends all the way to 3,140 rpm. The 1/3-horsepower motor will get the job done on small to medium jobs and common construction materials, including <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/janka-wood-flooring-hardness-rating-chart-1821655" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1" rel="noopener noreferrer">very hard woods</a>.</p><p>A cast iron base securely mounts to most worktables for a sturdy, stable hold. The included 6.5-inch x 6.5-inch beveling table is small but flexible, allowing you to tilt the drilling surface up to 45 degrees for angled drilling. This drill press has an 8-inch swing and a 2-inch stroke distance, meaning it's not designed to handle large, thick materials. The slots in the table are even large enough to accommodate mounting clamps and vises to secure the drilling surface to the table while tilting.</p><p>When it comes to drilling holes on the go, you probably think of <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/how-to-use-a-power-drill-1825112" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">handheld power drills</a>. While these are the go-to choice for hobbyists and professionals alike, most power drills lack the precision some jobs require. When you need an additional guide, a lightweight option like the Ogrmar Drilling Collet Drill Press comes in handy. This ingenious device is far easier to transport than is an actual drill press.</p><p>Instead of forcing you to lug around a dedicated drill press, this tool allows you to secure your existing power drill into a tight, rotating clamp. This clamp holds the drill along the metal rail, giving you the finer degree of precision you need without the extra weight. The clamp rotates from 0 to 90 degrees, so you can even precision drill on vertical surfaces if you can place the press in the correct position.</p><p>A dedicated floor drill press offers the most in terms of professional capability and features. The Delta 18-900L is a top-of-the-line option that maximizes the power, control, and durability you can have out of a drill press. If you have a dedicated workshop or professional projects, this type of drill is an investment that will last you a long time.</p><p>Many professionals prefer floor drills since they don’t take up table space and, in fact, typically offer larger work surfaces underneath the drill. The 18-900L includes a 20 x 28 inch worktable that bevels up to 90 degrees left or right. The 6-inch drill stroke is ideal for industrial applications or projects where larger parts such as 4 x 4 wood beams are common. The extra stroke length means you can drill deeper without having to make additional holes on the other side to connect, and the 18-inch swing lets you tackle even very large materials.</p><p>Drilling through metal is a different experience than working with woods or plastics. Since metal densities vary, you need a drill press that is highly adaptable for different types of metal. The DEWALT DWE1622k Magnetic Drill Press specializes in drilling through steel or similar metals with a two-speed, 10-amp motor and 4-inch drill travel. Its magnetic base lets you position the tool on any ferrous material that's at least 1/2-inch thick. The maximum size bit the tool can accept is 2 inches in diameter.</p><p>The press has overload protection electronics that prevent motor burnout and extend the life of the tool. It includes a coolant tank that you can position as needed while you work. The lower speed setting revs up to 300 rpm, and the higher setting is up to 450 rpm, allowing you to easily penetrate even very hard metals. At 35 pounds, the drill press is fairly heavy, but it’s a sturdy, powerful tool.</p><h2>What to Look for in a Drill Press</h2><h3>Swing</h3><p>The swing of a drill press is the measurement in inches from the chuck—the clamp that holds the bit in place—to the column, which is the thick metal pole supporting the drill press head, multiplied by two. So if the measurement from your drill press’s chuck to column is 5 inches, then the drill press has a 10-inch swing. Swing tells you the largest piece of wood or metal the drill press can accommodate while drilling a hole right in the center. The larger the swing, the larger materials a drill press can handle, so keep this in mind if you regularly work with big pieces of wood or metal.</p><h3>Stroke Distance</h3><p>Also called spindle travel or quill travel, the stroke distance is a measurement of how deep a hole the drill press can create without having to stop and readjust the drill press table or the material being drilled. Smaller or less expensive drill presses often have a mere 2.5-inch stroke distance, sometimes even a little less. Large, heavy-duty floor-standing drill presses can have as much as 6 or more inches of stroke distance, but most hobbyists or general DIYers won’t require this level of performance. As a general rule, around 4 inches of spindle travel is more than sufficient for most typical tasks.</p><h3>Floor or Benchtop Design</h3><p>There are two basic styles of drill press: floor and benchtop.</p><p>As the name suggests, floor drill presses are large tools that stand on the floor. These have a lot of power and typically a swing between 13 and 20 inches. Floor-standing drill presses are best for professional or heavy-duty use.</p><p>Benchtop drill presses sit on a workbench. These smaller machines generally have a swing between 8 and 12 inches, and handle light-to-moderate drilling tasks. Generally, these are the best choice for the average DIYer or hobbyist.</p><h2>FAQs</h2><h3>What else can you use a drill press for besides drilling holes?</h3><p>While the primary use of a drill press is to drill holes—particularly large-bore holes or holes that don’t go all the way through the wood—the tool has other uses, as well. With the right bit or attachment, your drill press can also be used to sand or clean wood and metal, drill square holes, deburr wood or metal, and polish or buff wood or metal surfaces.</p><h3>Can I use the same bits in my drill press and handheld power drill?</h3><p>As a general rule, as long as the shank size of the bit is not larger than your drill press’s chuck—the most common chuck size for a typical benchtop drill press is ½-inch—you can use the same bits with your drill press as you do with your corded or cordless power drill. Drill presses can handle larger diameter bits than the average power drill, however, which is one of the main benefits of these powerful tools.</p><h3>Is there any way to use a regular drill in place of a drill press?</h3><p>If you only need the precision of a drill press for one particular project, you might not want to invest in an entire tool just for that purpose. You can achieve similar results, however, as long as you don’t plan on drilling very large holes or into an exceptionally hard material, by using a frame designed to hold a corded or cordless drill in place as you use it. These frames rotate so you can position the drill just as you need it, and hold it far stiller during use than you’d be able to manage with your hand alone.</p><h2>Why Trust The Spruce?</h2><p>This article was written by <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/michelle-ullman-350447" data-component="link" data-source="inlineLink" data-type="internalLink" data-ordinal="1">Michelle Ullman</a>, the tool expert for The Spruce. She has extensive experience not only in writing about all things related to the home, but also in carrying out various DIY projects, including landscaping, painting, flooring, wallpapering, furniture makeovers, and simple repairs.</p></html></element></components><documentStyle><backgroundColor>#f6f6f6</backgroundColor></documentStyle><identifier>https://www.thespruce.com/best-drill-presses-4153445</identifier><language>en</language><layout><columns>7</columns><gutter>40</gutter><margin>70</margin><width>1024</width></layout><metadata><excerpt>
                A good drill press is powerful, easy to control, and durable. We researched the features of the best models so you can pick the right ones for your projects.</excerpt><thumbnailURL>https://www.thespruce.com/thmb/trJ5F48aBRwG7M-AlNnLRGfLgCY=/759x1500/715RIGooSGL._SL1500_-59ea5516845b340011e4144c.jpg</thumbnailURL></metadata><subtitle>Get more at <a href="http://www.thespruce.com">The Spruce</a>.</subtitle><title>
                A good drill press is powerful, easy to control, and durable. We researched the features of the best models so you can pick the right ones for your projects.</title><version>1.0</version></item>
    </channel>
</rss>
